Looking for unscheduled personal appearances,
only on the onset which is to address the counsel on any of the agenda items.
There are being none.
Item three is the consent agenda status,
about the many items four through nine for the consent agenda.
If there are no questions on any of those items,
I'd entertain the motion to approve.
Motion to approve.
And a second. Second.
A little call please.
Johnson.
Hi.
All right.
And item T, and this is exciting.
Splashpad presentation.
Ryan has only been waiting on this.
He doesn't own your hat.
So that's just a couple years ago.
All right.
This is something that I've been working in really hard
in the coalition lately.
Trying to get all this stuff situated.
On this Splashpad,
this is one drawing that we have come up with.
In your guys.
I handed out some of your pictures for you.
On that.
On this.
What you see here, there is actually 28 different sections
into this Splashpad.
Do we have anything we can share with audience?
We can share this around.
Yeah, we can share this around.
Yeah, because basically you've got to share this.
Right.
I know.
This just did not do well when we tried to do this.
Yeah.
Okay.
What do you think is going to be able to see that?
Spray right over here.
Yeah.
All right.
For a meal.
Yeah.
Block me.
One thing we can do after this presentation
to people are watching is why we try to put some of this on our website.
Yeah.
And that way people can go in a little bit later.
They can go.
Can we try this?
Didn't pee yet.
That's right.
That was why we printed these off.
So you were able to see it up?
Before we could do it all the way to us.
What are this is sitting on the land?
I guess.
This will actually be said in just behind the eagle picture building now.
Toward the back a little bit.
We are going to use that parking lot on the west side of the eagle picture building
for the parking lot for this on the west side.
Yes.
Okay.
And so this top earlier.
Is it running parallel to 9th?
Yes.
Oh, this is not straight right here.
The west side will be the state of Oklahoma.
It will be facing north.
The top border.
The border will be north.
Okay.
So it will be as you put on the driveway.
It will be you're walking in the pain handle.
You'll be coming in on the pain handle side of it.
Okay.
So.
On the parking lot.
Yes.
Yep.
Okay.
Good.
And then like you see, if you look at actually at the state.
You can see all those little squiggly lines inside that state.
That is actually the sections of features that will be in there.
There's 28 different sections in that.
In that within those sections.
there could be two, there could be five different play areas.
Just in there, like the total we actually in this still,
we have 24 ground flush mounts,
that shoot the water out of the ground.
There's actually 24 in this project.
We actually have two motorcycles.
We have a airplane.
And what we try to do is customize the city of Miami.
Everything, so the airplane is for the British flowers
with GRs, cemetery.
The motorcycles are for everybody who comes down Route 66.
We have all the motorcycles, build people that travel from 66.
So we're trying to bring in stuff in that is actually here in Miami.
And we actually have a, we put in a big super bucket splash pad deal,
the super bucket, and on that bucket it's going to look like
if you go to Pinch 2, you'll actually see the bucket
and get what we kind of actually put in there for it.
It'll set us to say in Hollywood, you know, actually say the Coleman,
you know, it'll be actually, it looks like a big bucket of popcorn.
So we'll actually have the Coleman there too.
Now, on these features, they range from different prices,
from around $1,000 to the bucket, from around $2,000 to the bucket, from around $2,000 to $2,000 to $2,000 to $2,000.
So they're going to be in those different price ranges.
Now, we did rotary has actually came to us to look at maybe helping
something out with this splash pad.
They actually had a couple of questions as far as the features on our
features for the splash pad.
What's the most popular features?
Which they are, the ground features, which is most ones,
the big bucket, and in the twirl buckets, the trio buckets,
in which we actually have one of those in the canons.
Well, actually I have two canons in this one too.
So the other deal was, what, the other question the head was,
two other splash pads have, that are more popular than what this one
doesn't have.
There's nothing in there in this splash pad that is not in
other splash pads.
So he said, what we have will keep these kids want to be there all day long.
And it's actually designed to rotate, to keep everything moving.
So that you keep the kids moving through the aquatic things
instead of a trial stand in there and just playing with the one.
It'll show off our little ball and then the next one.
So it moves them on into it and it rotates around so they get to enjoy everything
in the splash pad and not just one little thing.
And that's how you set it up.
You set it up to where each section has its own cycle.
So it keeps the kids moving flowing all through the park.
So it doesn't just keep them sitting in one spot.
So it's not activated by the kids or itself.
It's on the time.
Everything.
So they have no control over.
So you're able to shut it off at whatever time.
And you can actually set it up to where after like eight o'clock PM.
So some kid goes up there and he gets it.
It won't come on.
So you can.
actually control the part time by that time.
Are we anticipating fencing all the way around?
Yes.
That is one thing we will have as fencing.
Now we have not got quotes on the fencing yet that is something we're looking into.
And we are actually looking into like the rudder and fencing that's like we're on Joe Pollock right now.
We're about lighting.
Lighting will actually have to do lighting.
We'll have to put that in there too along the edge.
With lighting everything has to be underground.
With the splash pad with the grant all the power lines have to be underground.
So we'll actually have to run underground circuit for lighting for it.
But it depends on if you guys how you get light you guys want to leave it open too.
You know if you want it to go down the sundown we don't need lighting.
Sure.
I just didn't know if we'd call in any problem with Joe Pollock.
Maybe lighting or anything else.
And my intention is to shut it down at desk.
So I think having it lit up though even if it's not operational.
Good job.
Ben, it was awkward.
That's because of it.
Is the fence going to be high next to people?
Yes.
It'll be just like Joe Pollock.
Same height around it.
Try to keep everybody up.
We also talk to Oklahoma department.
While life yesterday we had a meeting with him.
I told him we got a grant with a Oklahoma tourism and told him about splash pad.
And asked if maybe they want to help out as far as bringing in the spoon bills.
Since we are spoon bill capital.
See if they want to maybe help sponsor something spoon bill in there.
He told me to get the design to him.
He thought it seemed like a really neat idea.
So maybe we can actually get them on board too.
We also have a meeting at March 15th with the Intertribal Council.
We're going to take this to him and see if maybe about them helping out.
And when we say help out, we're keeping them with exactly what needs.
And we are not.
We're not substituting what we would be spending and having somebody else.
That's over and above what we're going to be doing.
We are spending the amount of money on that grant regardless of if anybody helps out and on.
This would just make it bigger and better.
Is what?
And what do you say in square footage of that wall?
The square footage is actually a little bit of 6700.
It's huge.
A little bit of rest room piece of the goods.
You actually have 40,000 for restroom facilities set in the grant.
So it's actually set in there.
So we can actually build a restroom for it.
And I will actually, my deal on the rest room, put it a little bit out.
It'll be outside the fancy area, but a little bit to the right.
So we can use multi-tast that restroom if we ever do.
You know, maybe bringing BMX or something over there.
I've had some citizens ask about water consumption and then estimated coordination costs.
And coordination, there will be no coordination.
We're actually going to be a three-feet.
So it actually come out of our drinking water.
Go right through.
And you can actually just that split in the control panels.
There's coming, this is going to be a potable water that comes directly from our water supply.
And then it will go out into the center, or just straight to the center, exactly.
But you need to see how much water consumption on the...
And you can adjust that.
I know grilled use is a million a day that we looked into.
They use a million gallons a day.
But you can actually adjust it to whatever water flow as you want.
I know when we went and looked at big speeds, there's just kind of triple that.
To save the water consumption on it.
And it only lasted the whole cycle when we did like five minutes.
And then the water pressure was very low.
So like I said, you can adjust it to have much water pressure.
These buckets here, they fill up in the nice, very free.
And as far as maintenance, when and maintenance, it's very minimal.
You take the buckets down, you store them inside.
You wax it with the spring coming around, you blow off the concrete.
You wax the features, put your buckets back on, and that's it.
I think it's going to be very popular.
Typically, you grow how many months a year or a day open.
That I do not know.
I know that as far as when I looked at big speed, they said they usually open their zip.
Roughly right around with pooled-less.
And then they leave, there's open all the way into like September October and shut it down.
Because you don't have to have a lifeguard on duty.
It's about five to six months.
Yeah.
And as long as the weather's warm during the day and you've got young parents that want to take their kids
that never scheduled not a Monday through Friday, and they have two days off.
And they can take their their young kids to the to the splash pad and have to make that day as opposed to having to take it.
Are we looking seven days a week?
Yes.
Seven days.
I do know he asked about capacity as far as how many people could use it at one time.
He did say there's really not a set standard like for a pool.
So, but he said with square footage of stuff, he's looking around 150 to 200 people can use this once.
What?
A lot of people.
And you have a rough budget.
I mean, I know we've got a plan.
We've talked about that.
Well, you see right here is 420,000.
It comes in under what our grand was for was for the 583.
That also gives us room for the bathrooms and other stuff.
It's far as fancy and lighting and stuff like that.
Which we can take, like you said, you know, who I've been talking is not in stone.
So, we can lessen that as far as features and stuff like that and say money on that side to put maybe build a better bathroom.
Or, you know, we can fluctuate all that stuff.
How long is going to take from start to finish?
I'm struggling.
When people I talk to, so it takes about 6 months to build it.
They was helping, if the building was gone, and they could...
started it in January, they would have had it here by May, June. So you're looking around six
months to build it. When are we looking at cutting up building, John? We're still hoping the building
will be coming down in April. I did get a little bit of information that on the bidding,
there's going to be a little bit slower on the bidding because I had to put their bid,
our chains are bid specs a little bit. When I say they, I'm talking about Oklahoma Department
of Environmental Quality. So what we're doing right now is with tourism, we're working very closely
with them. So far, they told us the delays that might come in the demolition are not going to
be putting our grant at risk. I would also like to point out that with ODE, you're taking down that
building, I've heard estimates that that's about a half a million dollar project right there.
So that gives you an idea of what the state's putting in for this as well. So we need to be a little
patient because they're probably easily going to be spending as much taking that building down
as we are to go to splash pad. They did also, I talked to Susan Henry with Oklahoma to
tourism who we got the grant through, told him about DQ, you know, we're waiting on them.
She said if the building is done by April, the state does it in sections as far as releasing the money.
So she said if it's done by April, we can have a June 1 start date to break down. If we do not meet
that deal, then we will have to wait till July before they will actually give us a start date in August.
So it will be right by this dollar. But we're in no risk of losing that grant because we're going to
risk to the light. We don't have a more much. She knows DQ is involved and she said just keep a timeline
in the loop. They're fine with it. This is a great demonstration project for both the
EQ and tourism because you know when we got a conference as we hear the term great fields all the time.
And this is a perfect example of taking an old industrial building and converting it into
a facility for the park. One final thing is we often talk about that chlorine plume and again we'll
be working very closely. DQ, I believe the plume is actually further to the east of that.
So where the plume has been identified, that is not where this is going to be going.
And also what DQ is telling us is that one of the problems with that plume is that it's the building
is on top of it. Once the building is removed, that will just naturally dissipate into the environment
and will actually correct itself. So what we're doing here is it's not like the Bensing
plume it would be a good rich in any way shape or form and we will never put that facility anywhere close to
where that plume is. So people when they use it will be safe. Awesome. Any other questions? Thank you.
Yeah, for sure, very much.
OK, item 11 is designation of two
loading zone parking spaces and three
two hours spaces in the unit block of
each central on the south side of the road.
Hi, Christine Chief.
Hello.
Good.
When the red onion owner Jim Hardy came
and approached the city about working
working with him and getting his business up
and going, one of his
concerns was what is typically known as
carryout parking, where you can pull up
and park for just a few minutes running
into your meal, and then also long-term parking.
That normally happens on that section of the block
right there where he's going to be located.
So he approached us about what we might be
able to do and we told him that, you know,
based on our ordinances, that we could do
two loading zones that would allow for, you know,
quick use by any customer, any, you know,
his customers, any of the customers that are down there,
as long as it's, you know, like, 15 minutes run in and
do something and come back.
That's not designated for his business.
No, it's just going to be designated for his business.
It's going to be just a loading zone.
And then we could also earmark those three spaces
at the end that are marked in yellow and the rest
of that block as two-hour parking.
So that I think right now what we see there is long-term parking,
like somebody will park there and they'll be there all day.
And so this will ensure that there's good turnaround on those
parking spots for customers that might use the restaurant
or customers that might utilize the bank or the insurance
company or any of the businesses in that area right there.
And if you all approve, designating those, then high-target can go out
and make sure that the signs are posted and we can move forward.
I know it's not shown on the coast, but is there additional parking?
I'm going to say that.
Or my insurance.
On Main Street?
No, behind.
There's a municipal parking lot.
It's a South with a yes.
So there's parking right here.
There's still a little bit of parking here and then back over here.
Yeah, that's where I was going to be.
A city parking lot.
And on Main Street itself, there's quite a bit of two-hour parking there too.
For a security bank, it's kind of where the red onion in all of those businesses
are all in there.
Good.
Is the parking in front of Gallagher, is that long-term or is that two-hour?
also. No, it's, it's not marked. Okay. So the yellow that will be marked. Now the yellow will be marked.
The two red ones will be marked as loading zones and the two yellow ones will be marked as two
hour parking. I'm sorry the three yellow ones. Thank you. We'll be two hour parking. So they'll be
rotate it out. Exactly. Yeah. Any concerns? Any questions? When the, how long does
somebody take this once it's approved? It should be very like all the signs. Public works already
knows. They're just waiting for your approval and then they'll be ready. I don't know if it's
like that. Do they have an anticipated opening? Not up like one. And officially. They've told us
that probably right around the first week of April. So it's coming up very quickly. But that's
really got a cut in place. That's good enough. That's good enough. That's good enough. That's good enough.
That was about the other day and they have red in the signs on the doors. Yes. Thank you. And they're hiring.
That's right. Do you think maybe you'll see the question, but on these yellow ones, would be a thought
of if after hours five o'clock that they didn't have a timely one on. That would do.
That would, this, if you go a block east in front of you central pond, those are one hour spots in there
marked eight to five. On block the other way in front of Osborne's a 30 minute parking. So the whole
down kind of area is very diverse with the parking limits. They would definitely depend on the needs.
I don't know what the hours will be for this facility. If they're not designated for that restaurant,
if they're just general eight five would be fine. If it's designed for their customers,
I think they would want to probably do business hours. I don't know what their hours would be.
If I'm just saying at the bank or by closing in at five o'clock, you would probably just be right
on traffic anyway. Right. I'm okay either way. I mean, I would go on cheese recommendation, whatever he thinks.
I think if you'd head off at five, that's kind of defeat in the purpose. Don't they want to open so people can park there to go for dinner?
Yeah, and the parking correct me if I'm wrong on this.
Chief, if the parking on Main Street in several places, it's marked just as two hour parking.
So this, this is in line with the other parking signs that are already on Main Street.
Just two hour parking.
And we don't have a parking enforcement per se. We don't mark tires every night.
Go to the table.
on a complaint basis would any of the partners down town.
So, it wouldn't be, what are no more partners over two hours to generate complaints?
It's, it's, it's, it's, it's, it's four of those on complaint basis.
Okay.
And well, we're working with Jim, we've let him know that.
For those spaces, that it's more advisory, if he sees somebody abusing it, he needs to call
us a week and then force it that by you passing his ordinance that then will allow police officer
to write a citation for somebody who doesn't use that.
Helen, I would hope we'd rather I'm probably a warning the first time around because it's
people that work on town that are blocking the town.
Also one other thing I've asked, I asked Steve Gilbert if he would contact business owners
in the area and let them know what we're doing and he has done that.
I think we've had really a lot of positive feedback because I think everybody's really
thrilled that Redine is coming.
Yeah, it was pretty much all positive because what he wanted is your customers to park
their customers of the different businesses that are located right there.
And they all benefit from having that rotation available.
And I think the 15 minutes of good idea too.
That means if you literally need to get out so I can get in.
If you don't buy walking a little bit, there's going to be plenty of places to park me.
Yeah, further south of the city.
Yeah, I think that's spot.
Yes.
Right, that means I used to be with those two spots.
So is this an ordinance?
No, that we already have an ordinance.
You just have to approve dedicating those.
Okay, spaces as we have listed here and then the chief can take it from there.
Okay, do you, if there are no more questions, do we have a motion?
Yes, I'll move.
Second, second, go call please.
Lewis, I, Weston.
Aye.
Forster.
Johnson.
Aye.
Schultz.
Okay, I'm following one is two one seven national four meaning section 2462 which is
removal research, which is scheduled to removal resource net metering.
Mr. Andrew, how are you, Mr. Mayor and Council?
I'm good.
Thank you.
The staff has been busy working with GTA and looking at our own ordinances with what to do with renewable resources.
And what I've sent out to you on, on, is for background information, it's just,
only bring you up a day just a little bit of where this came from.
What happened in 1978, the fans came up with what's called the Purple Act.
The Purple Act is 57 pages long.
Basically what it says is,
is that people can put up renewable resources and the electric utility that serves them has to pay
them for any additional power output out in the lines.
And so just about every utility in the United States, accepted this and went along just fine,
and we at North East Electric Co.
I did too, just like the city did.
In 2001, the city came up with an ordinance that was established, that's what established
section 2462, which is currently called the Renewable Resource Purchase Schedule, which
among other requirements requires a city to purchase excess power from Renewable Resource
Providers.
In 2014, the city had its first official Renewable Resource Person come to you and say, I want
to do this.
And in doing so, the attorney at that time, we sat down and he said, well, but the building
to part was going to have to pay you every month, can we work out a deal that, you know,
what would be a good way to change the ordinance to take care of that?
I said, essentially, the way to do that would be to let them accumulate whatever they want
to, and at the very end of the contract, we pay out in that type of thing, at wholesale rates.
So since that time, the staff has had meetings, and in the meetings, we have talked about
Jill, in fact, if I may drop a name here, brought up a good point in our meeting, and that
was, but at the end of the contract, that means that the city has a liability, hanging out
there all this time that there may have to pay some amount to a customer, and that got me to
thinking.
So I started to read, I went back and read that 57 pages of the purple act.
And as it was, the city does not, does not have to abide by the purple act.
Purple act only goes to cities that sell 500 million kilowatt hours or more.
The most the city is ever sold, is 216 million kilowatt hours, and that was in 2015.
So we don't, and probably won't, for many, many, many years, have to fall under this act.
But as a matter of fact, this act also is stated within our GRDA contract, and if we did fall
under GRDA, make arrangements to purchase power and do things with us that we could take
here.
But in that we don't, we have an all requirements contract with GRDA that says we cannot
buy power from anybody else.
We have to buy it from GRDA.
So in looking at all this, we discuss this.
and say, well, the way to do this is to essentially rewrite the ordinance somewhat, change
a title of it, and we have changed a title from renewable resource, purchases schedule,
which is not, it's not a schedule anymore. It has nothing to do with utility billing. If somebody
comes out and puts up a solar panel on a house, they'll have to come to the city just like
the way that they put in a welder, welding circuit, you'd have permit to put in the electrical
connection after it's after it's done, then the inspector would come out and inspect it and
it's all over, said and done with. They can generate as much powers they want to, in excess
power that they generate, though, would be used by the city. They'll never get reimbursed forever.
That's what's called net metering without being reimbursed for it. If somebody decides that
they want to put up some big solar farm or whatever like that within the city, as far as
the sea's concerned, we don't have any ordinance that allows us to do that. That could be done
through negotiations with the city manager, the council, and GRDA, because it would have to be sold
a GRDA, and GRDA would have to be reimbursed us back for it. That's how that part would work,
and there's already that language in the contract, and we've looked through that.
And only if we're selling 500 million kilowatt hours?
No, no, not even at that. We don't have to buy any power from anybody. We do not follow
under the purple act at all. Because we don't fall under the purple act, our contract would
be a GRDA in the case that we cannot buy power from anybody else.
That's correct. Thank you, sir.
So anyway, my recommendation is, and by the, and, and, and, and managed been through the contract,
I mean, through the ordinance. He's looked at that. There's one thing in your, in this, this section,
the last page. Well, it says, I moved approve. Are you on the right one?
Anyway, the recommendation is that the effective date needs to be changed,
Christa, from March 7th to April 6th. We had recommended in, I had written in the, in the ordinance
for the, the, the, the, the, the, the emergency. Thank you. Emergency clause, which we don't, we don't need it all.
We thought we wanted to do this as quick as possible, but it's not an emergency. So that needs to be
structural. It'll be 30 days. This is when this would go into effect.
And so in effect, all we're saying is we don't fall under the purple act, and if somebody
installs solar panels on their roof, and there's a,
And they don't use all the power and the difference comes to the city.
We just gain that and we don't pay any.
That's exactly right.
Yeah.
And that's in effect all we're stating and changing by approving this.
In effect, we're sitting a limit.
The limit is 20,000 kilowatt hours a year access.
They would put back out on the system.
And, or excuse me, a hundred KW of capacities.
And you won't see that.
That's just, we just put that in as an absolute maximum.
There is one other caveat to this, too, that we put in there.
This is not in the ordinance now.
And that is that we do have the right to charge some small fee for a meter adjustment.
Remember, all the meters in our city go up every month.
Hopefully go up every month.
They don't go down.
They don't go in a negative direction.
Right now it's being done by hand until we go to some other type of a billing apparatus or whatever
where it can pick up negative numbers.
And as a staff discussed, we wanted to have that in there.
It would be zero for right now.
But it is in there and gives us the right to charge some small.
If we have a dozen or so, it can be done.
But if we have a hundred and fifty two hundred, we probably would want to do that because our staff would have to make those adjustments.
So, we just cross that bridge and we come to it.
And so, we're not in violation of our agreement with GRDA because we're not buying power from somebody we're getting for you.
That's correct.
Yeah.
We're not purchasing power.
And I'm going to tell you that 90% of the people that would put up solar panels are not like
Dr. Mark and myself.
These are the people that are going to put out a few panels thinking it's the right thing to do.
It's a green thing.
And their new products coming down the line very soon that probably changed the way we all live.
When you look at some of the things Tesla is talking about and all that.
It might seem exotic now.
But iPhone seemed very exotic 10 years ago.
So, the world is changing, and this is a way to start dealing with it.
If you don't have it, this is my recommendation.
My recommendation.
Thank you.
Any questions for David any concerns?
I just would like to ask, Ben, if he, I know he's looked over in all my theories.
Okay.
Then do you have any concerns?
No, I don't.
I get what the effect in David.
April 6, instead of March 7, since there's no emergency clause in it.
would be the required 30 days for something to go into effect.
Actually, it should be March, or I'm sorry, April 7.
But you don't count today.
OK.
So if there are no other questions, I'm going to read this.
I'll make the motion.
And then if someone wants to set it, they can.
I moved to approve the Modifying Inception 24-262.
I'm going to be a resource purchases schedule to renewable resource net metering as presented with an effective date of April 7, 2017.
I'll second down there.
OK.
Work all please.
So, hi.
Johnson.
Lewis, I question.
Hi.
For sir.
Thank you.
Thanks, David.
I'm 13.
I'm a travel information center.
And the programming of the photo gallery, the Ronin Gilbert Family Tourism Gallery.
Hi.
You're all a nice person.
It's not being in your package.
It's just kind of...
Got this one.
I got this one.
Thanks.
OK.
So just a few updates to bring you up to speed.
And the last time I was here, we were asking for approval for to take over operations.
And obviously, we've done that as of January 28.
Just a few things.
We actually got the official MAU in the now today from Claremont.
So that one is...
That one is done.
Bottle's goal.
We should be getting that one confirmed.
Hopefully, by the end of this week, she has her meeting this week.
We have meetings.
These are our partnerships that we talked about.
Went to the media a couple weeks ago.
That one looks very promising.
I meet with growth and convention and tourism bureau.
And some of their councilmen on March 23 to confirm that.
And then we've got information out to South Graham Lake Chamber, the Tulsa CVB and also Graham Lake Association.
So all those are coming on board as we anticipated.
And just a few updates.
Kind of the next step.
You can see there in my report.
Obviously, the finalizes MAUs.
The next thing is to get our racks put out there with all the brochures, all the information.
Get the TV split up.
The photos, all the things that we had promised to our partners.
And just revamping retail to try to work on bringing those revenues up a little bit.
I put some numbers there just so you guys can kind of see.
We were down two weeks.
You know, we closed.
The first week, just so we could go out and, you know, we had tons of resources on the city side.
A lot of different departments over hands on that went out and worked on some just getting the transition done that week.
So we were down one week.
The second week.
It took about all that week to get quick books.
We were going to sell system up and going.
That was a little bit of a process because that was the only thing the state did not let us keep.
If you'll recall, we couldn't keep their computers or their retail system.
So we had to do that from the ground.
So we only had about two weeks of profit for February. You can see there. We brought in $4,900 and $1.81.
In the month of February and then six days into March we brought in $1,290 and $75.
So revenues are starting to roll. What's the difference?
Basically, postcards and a lot of snacks, water, bottled, shand and ice, but some time today going through the reports.
It's a lot of snacks, t-shirts, pins that you can put on like biker pins that you can put on your jackets, just her, her random stuff.
So we're working with a couple of different companies now for some different retail ideas, some kind of some jewelry.
And then Shandai are getting the paperwork completed so that we can get into the made-in-up-al-home market and then in the future get into the Dallas market to be able to go and get some product that we can bring back.
Another thing you must, it's something we talked about. You can hold it the state about, I know they talked about the exit, off to this place.
They made some sign each and I was just curious, but when I drove by at the other night coming back from job, it was dark.
It means dark out, but the buildings dark and I'm wondering, what is our ability to put any form of lighted sign on the building?
Actually, Ben with Ben's help, we had a very positive meeting with Tim Gets, the director of the OTA, of turn by authority.
They're crafting a letter right now which would be a letter of agreement.
And in essence, where the building is concerned that attitude is everything on the inside of the sidewalk around the building is ours.
So if we wanted to do some things along that line, that's not a problem. They're going to take care of the asphalt, they're going to take care of the lighting around the building.
And also that we've talked to them about helping us out with some of the signage and they're very open to that, we just need to come up with what we want.
And also, they were like a special event or something like that, they'd be been indicated they would put temporary signs.
If you're entering on Missouri, a temporary sign on the side of the road that would tell that there's some type of a special event and to stop it.
So we're starting to develop that relationship right now with OTA, but it was a very positive meeting.
So along that line, I think as long as we've worked with them, told them what we wanted to do.
Again, the lighting around the building, everything OTA will be taken care of that.
If we wanted to work something up, I think they'd be very open to us.
I thought, well, I'd be, you know, as it's dark, because you're running through there, if you had anything to say to my M or whatever.
We'd be good every time.
What would they have?
Well, the hour.
It's up in from 8.30 to 5, 7 days a week.
So I was coming back about six o'clock one night and I was going to pull in there and it was dark.
And I thought, I didn't know.
Okay.
Yeah, so you can see right now what our estimates are between now and the end of June is to bring in about $45,000 of revenues into retail.
Just a little staffing update we have you're saying revenues and you're saying profit and those aren't the same so now I'm saying
Well, it would on now wouldn't be total profit this would be revenues. These are her estimates of what she sold over the last two years an average
From March to June was 45,000 in retail so that wouldn't actually be profit
That's just gonna be our revenue in so your first numbers that you gave as a few minutes ago
Really need to say revenue. Oh, yeah, thank you for putting that out and
Staffing we you know we brought Shanda over which had been there. She's under seventh years
So she's our full-time person. We've got two of our what we call our part-time 12 month
Staff people and then we've got two of what we call our part-time seven month our season. Oh, that's just there on the peak time
The peak time so we actually have two positions up when we're trying to fill right now
So that's just kind of on the operational side and
So like everything's been great a little bit of the transition on Melinda's here and we spent some time together
After today's we've got some good PR that's getting ready to roll out and then really getting ready to launch
So I'm marketing and some branding for the center with our partners the other item. You can see in front of you
One of the things that we talked about in our partnership program to help with revenues is
What we're calling a tourism gallery so you've got the actually some of the renderings that have been finalized
You can see that in the picture. It's the it's the comment and you can see that there's websites the city of Groves picture
And is promoting with Creek Park they're new fishing
Destination that they've done you can see bottles bills the price tower with their website and then we have one for
British flyers Claire more still working on what photo they want so these will be when you walk into the center
They're on the north wall when you walk in
It's the big large wall to the right and it's going to be a photo
Gallery and every partner that basically buys into our program will have a 16 by 20
It'll be a very nice canvas framed
Picture the ones that you see are the ones that have been finalized so far the thought is is to actually I kind of did it's not gonna be
Exactly this, but I wanted something just for you guys to have as a visual
We did find this picture and you know the ideas because of Dr. Gilbert and Anne and their service that they've been to tourism over the years
It's to be able to recognize them and one of the ways that we thought would be appropriate as we actually
We'll work with our vendor input a sign up there that would say they're on an and Gilbert family tourism gallery and we would have all the
Let Colby go out there, you know a range of subject professional with all the canvases and all of that so
That's what we're bringing to you guys tonight
They're well-deserving
Yeah
Any questions do we
Walking before we run, but are we need talks about expanding the hours right now?
It would be a staffing bill. I would say
kind of what I vision is probably at least maybe in 90, 90 days in business and just to kind of see where we're at.
Chanda's done a good job of working with what she has right now because we are two people down.
So we've been rotating CVB employees out there to fill the gaps in, but also to cross-strain.
I can see us possibly down the road depending on if we can increase revenues and have that to offset those personnel expenses.
I definitely think that's something we could look at.
And so at that time it's been a year since I stopped there.
I don't know what's in that way appear if I just come home, but the restrooms are there on the inside or the accessible from the outside.
You enter from the inside to go to the restrooms.
So for years they had the restrooms open 24-7.
There were some other centers that it just, when there's not anybody out there monitoring it, there's a lot of vandalism.
There was actually in the Oklahoma City Center that somebody had died in the restrooms and they've the employees discovered that the next morning.
So there's a lot of things that state tourism kind of, you know, took a step back and said we're across the board.
We're going to go ahead and close when operations are closed.
We're going to close the restrooms as well.
Okay.
The revenues from the state brewery, who had they compared the last February.
Well, they're down.
She ran about 15,000, but we were down.
And we were closed for two weeks.
So in her traffic count last year we, she and I looked at this today actually.
So her traffic counts were a little bit higher.
People coming in the center last February, then they were obviously even with the two weeks Bayon.
So for some reason we are counter off on visits.
So just one of those years last year that she had more feet in there and they had a really good month themselves.
Yeah, next year, day last year too.
So I mean, I think we'll catch up.
You know, we've, she has started the process of working with purchasing and finance.
I've getting some of the vendors that they've used online.
And then we're getting ready to start doing some restocking of some items.
I'm just going to catch up.
Just be clear.
I mean, there are these on the staffing and so there's two positions open.
That's both part time.
Okay.
One is a part time.
I think it closes Friday.
It's open right now.
It is a part time up to 25 hours a week and it's for 12 months.
And then the other position in the budget is what we consider just during our peak time.
And that's like hermo about March to about September, October.
And that's 25 hours a week.
But it's not.
It's just during kind of a seasonal type of position.
Were there any new full time positions added to the city roles?
Well, it would have been Shandas.
Shandas would have came over as.
Yeah.
Sorry.
We knew what it is.
But we did last week when we put the three annoying positions.
No, because I think when we brought those on board, we were still below.
We weren't.
Yeah.
The limit.
doing the three started bumping us about the limit of all the time.
Okay.
So, Shane, didn't put us over the top, it was the top of the three, put us over the top, correct?
Does something like this might be inside of the travel system?
Absolutely.
We can put a rendering out there with, I mean, I, one of the things we're working really
close with, Alicia and Jamie, we met yesterday, a couple of different times, about some
things and some, is branding and signage, you know, have been able to, once we get this
with the splash pad branded, really taking that and trying to do some directional signage
around the community that's all the same brand that, really tells our story and we'll
have all that out there at the, at the travel center too.
Now, these pictures on the wall, there's just one for each community that buys the end, but
on the TV, they get 25 rows of things, and that's moving forward.
We priced all those out today, Kevin and his crew got the wall mounts ordered those came in this
week, so that's, that's all moving forward.
Still, a little bit of issue with cable out there, you know, we were hopeful that we were
going to be able to get some cable out there, that's one of the questions that visitors asked.
They want to know what's going on, especially during the springtime.
Right now, Shanda, tries to pull the computer screen around the side, where they can see the weather
channel from the desktop, so we were hopeful that we could get cable random those TVs out right
there, and right now, the expense is just too much, really, in the beginning stages of us
trying to get our, you know, figure out for sure what operations are going to look like.
Can't, this is a lot.
It's a IT question, that's my IT guy.
He's been busy with it, that's not what I want to talk about, he's been so ready that you can
stream off your computer with a switch over to a monitor or a TV for, like, weather and
stuff, but not have to do that.
Can you answer that, we can talk with the man.
Okay.
We can do that.
Perfect.
Yeah.
And the other thing we might go back and look at is our cable contract, I mean, one time we had
not remember the number, but we had the right to a certain number of cable hook ups
as part of our franchise agreement, and maybe we were using them all, I just don't remember.
I just know that that wasn't laws in the contract.
One of the things we were looking at right now is a possibility of wiring the one bolt, and
we're taking a look at other city facilities too, that we would be able to do that.
I think that would probably be the more positive thing that would really get it to where
we, you talked about adding Wi-Fi out there that people will be able to have Wi-Fi be able
to attract that.
So, I think one of the problems we might have, and I'm only speculating on this, but any standard
contract with a cable company, they're not required to locate any place that's isolated.
You know, that he cost of running that.
So I don't know if that would fall into that.
If cable one would not be required under our agreement to be able to have to run a cable
that fall out.
It was going to, I think the ballpark for cable one to do that was about $7,000.
I think that's right, David.
And that meaning is about $7,000.
And we just, just wasn't something we had in the budget at this time.
So.
I, I thought it was so unfair.
It's just a question of.
They're on TV.
We don't want to have to wait that long, but they may start doing some infrastructure there that we could tie into.
So if you talk to the Gilbert?
I have not.
No.
They're going to be surprised.
Well.
Unless you're watching to well deserved it.
Try to hide it from him a little bit.
Okay.
Any other questions?
I'm excited that we're doing this.
I think it's going to be a good source to the community and to people traveling through.
So what is keep blowing ahead?
Thank you, Amanda.
I am 14 new business dean.
Not from ER.
Okay.
Mayor and Council committee announcements.
I will just talk again about the charter election, which is coming up on the fourth of April.
Right.
Anydemotion to do that officially?
Sorry to me.
Okay.
So we have a promotion to approve the naming of the federal gallery, the Rowling Union, Gilbert Family,
Tourism Gallery.
Do we have a second?
I'll second.
Will call please?
Short.
I can.
Lewis.
Johnson.
All right.
Weston.
Thank you.
So now we were at I am 15.
Council and announcements.
And we have a charter election coming up on April 4th.
I believe that the text of the revised text of proposed text of the new charter has been published twice.
In the news record and scheduled be published a third time this Sunday, along with a guest at a toilet
A letter from me with some help from some other people.
It is an attempt to kind of explain why we're asking the citizens to consider voting, voting in any charter.
It talks a little bit about some of the shortcomings of our current charter.
It was great when it was first written 100 and something years ago, but it's been added on to and cobbled and since then, and it's time for us to really take a fresh look.
And we really need to update it because there's some aspects of it that aren't replying what kind of law.
Lots of different things.
I would appreciate anybody that's watching the dentures to the police take the time to look at the Sunday pay for it.
Look at it and read the guest editor that we're going to try to have in there again explaining some of the details.
So, I'll please walk for that and then we have our work sessions scheduled for March 28.
We're going to hold it in the ballroom next door and invite the public to come and ask questions.
questions and we'll all be there to try to answer any questions that they might have and that'll be the week before the election.
So hopefully we'll have a good turnout and be able to answer any questions or concerns that citizens might have.
I think that's all I've got on that. Anything else?
Well we just went through all class reunion in Rikian and the good Rikian, and concert Friday night.
If you most of the concert Friday night, you must have a great concert.
We're already working a little bit on next year.
We might tweak it a little bit and we're going to get there.
But it was a good Rikian and the program next year.
Okay.
I say major communications.
Might have damaged from the windstorm last night.
Fortunately, we weren't hit nearly as hard as a lot of places up north.
A little bit of advanced damage at Joe Pollock, which has already been taken care of.
We just found out that we might have some damage in the scoreboard.
It turned out to be a brighter.
We're wonderful.
So we're glad to see that.
You know, a few down tree limbs at the street was on top of a couple of private buildings that had a little minor wind damage.
But that's good to report.
We didn't have that much.
So we got it through.
And I think that was the first time you got to spend the evening at the EOC.
Hi, Taylor.
Yeah.
So thank you very much for that.
I appreciate that.
One of the things that we normally would have done otherwise on this agenda.
I'd number the things that Tyler presented to you.
We might have put those on a consent agenda.
But we're going to try to take those off the consent agenda because it's part of what our
Compliance is talking about our capital and private plans.
We have a number of other things that are going to be coming up the next few meetings.
I did ask staff to give me an idea.
We're still working on that water line improvement on 125th the boring.
We are working on designs for a web central both for the utilities and the construction there.
Truck route.
We're trying to get grants for that.
We're working with Grant Gateway on the truck route to do a complete rebuild there.
Microsoft is saying we hope to have the Microsoft is in contract to you in April and then get the work started in May.
Much like we did last year except get it done much earlier in the year than we did.
I know that Alicia is probably also working on a kind of a maintenance schedule with our crews.
We'll be doing too.
Now that we've got the building season coming up.
And then also.
Exactly.
That's exactly what I was going to get to that next.
And then also.
Doing some additional work on the.
Main Street program or Main Street project for the common and the drainage.
I think probably we're taking a hard look at some of the drains that we're going to have to do on that one.
So anyway, a lot of these projects we're not talking about them lately, but yes, we're working on it very much.
Let's talk about neighborhood cleanup just the details and what's going to.
So do you want to clean up.
Christine.
Sorry.
I know.
Let's get along the.
My focus.
We actually have almost made it through all of the really bad sections of town and as of
Yesterday, I think it was like 52500 and 30
Some odd notices had been
Given out so those are the notices that the code officers are going up and down
The streets and the alleys
letting those citizens know that they've got
Code compliance issues that can be
addressed if they take advantage of the community why clean up so there'll be a
It'll take us a little while after you know seeing the numbers come in to get our hands around
The follow up on it, but we will go back to every address
that we've recorded that we've posted and
See if they realize it's been for now all we need to get out is just the information about the cleanup itself
When it gets started when areas of town
What we we have meeting today with Tyler and
Jamie and Mike and my
I'm so loud I worry about being too loud at the microphone and we have got
County that is going to help us we have got
Both of our great alls and we are going to start Monday morning at 730 and we're going to start in the green acres area
We're going to come all the way through town and we will pick up the
regular trash that they put out for
The city wide clean up please keep in mind we're not going to be picking up just regular household trash that you would normally put in your polycard
This is for your catches and and things like that we are going to have a brush truck
We're going to have a
metal truck and then we will have just a regular and they'll rotate around
We're going to work our way all the way through
The west side of town and then we will come back and we'll make one more pass
So we'll make two complete passes in order to try to make sure we get everything taken care of
Would you please tell the dates?
So somebody watching knows when they can put things at the curb
And we'll just begin on your west side of town and we will start Monday morning on the 13th as I said and we will start picking it up then
We will go all that week on that side the next week. We will start on the east side
Which is more of a way to solve the 20 years of this coming week
Yes, the west the complete west side of town okay the complete east side of town will be the following week
Which will be on the 20th and we will do the same thing. We will go through both sides of town twice
So we'll go and heal area be that's the west side. Yes, if you have south west on your on your address
Then you are considered on the west side of town even though you are on on the other side of the bridge
That's always been hard for me to remember is that your south west part down is actually the west side of town
complete this at Monday morning at 7.30, you've got another
opportunity.
But they haven't been there stuff out the weekend before.
Just to make sure that one of the things that I've noticed is I've been
driving around town is the stuff being put out is their dumpster, their regular
trash receptacle is right in the middle of it, and it won't for the guys to
pick it up, that needs to be moved out of the way so that they can get a clear
pickup of the debris that's at the corner.
And this will not interrupt your regular trash schedule.
The folks that whatever regular day that your trash is picked up, your trash will still
be picked up that regular day.
Where your trash dumpster should be, is that, or just, no, that's, that's, that's
she's, separate it out, make it, we're gonna, we have honestly seen a whole, what
we call it, the link of someone's property.
Okay.
So we will pick it up, we will pick it up, we will pick it up, we will pick it up, we will
pick it up.
Thank you, we will.
Now, auto website will have the details about the dates and the times to get it out.
We have already put that out there, yes, okay, thank you.
So when I was out of town last month, my daughter called me and said, did you leave town this
way?
Because you knew they were going to close all the railroad crossings, and so I said, no, but I knew
that was coming, but I wasn't sure where it was going to be.
So, whatever was that we done with that, as well, remember, that was not our project.
I'm not one of our projects, we understand that it's done, okay, yes, okay, any other, any other
announcements?
No, okay, we are going to quickly move into executive session, pursuant to 25 over that's 307,
be warned for the purposes of discussing employment hiring, employment promotion, the motion,
you're supporting it, it's setter.
Do we have a motion to be going to executive session for the reasons outline in agenda item 17?
Okay, motion, or so go call please.
I'm sorry.
Good to meet you.
Good to meet you in the evening.
I'm asking.
I'm sorry.
Friday, the 17th.